你在干嘛
What are you doing?
帮谢尔顿检查有没有鸽子
Pigeon check for Sheldon.
北面检查完毕
North side's all clear!
太好了  来观测星球吧
Great. Let's look at some planets!
为什么要把你的望远镜大老远拖过来啊
Hey, why'd you lug your telescope all the way over here?
家里莱纳德也有一个啊
Leonard has one in our apartment.
对对对  要我用莱纳德的那个
Yeah, I'm gonna use Leonard's.
还不如干脆把我的手卷成这样再眯眼看
Might as well hold my hand up like this and squint.
还好吧  感觉他那个还不错啊
I don't know. It seemed pretty good.
有一次我们家有线电视没了
You know, once when the cable went out,
我用那个看对街一户人家的电视
I watched an entire episode of The Bachelor
看了一整集真人秀《单身汉》
on a TV across the street.
这个是比较专业的模型
This one's more of a professional model.
男主角选的也是专业的模特啊
So was the girl he picked!
我这宝贝是有着十寸直径的f1/10光圈的ACF望远镜
This baby's got a ten-inch diameter with f/10 ACF optics.
而今晚  水星会达到东大距
And tonight Mercury is at its highest elongation.
行星与太阳之间分离的角度达到最大时称为大距
水星离太阳太近  达到大距公众才好观测
那会让很远的东西看起来近一点
It makes far-away things seem close,
另外  水星是一个行星
and Mercury is a planet.
我知道水星是行星
I know Mercury is a planet.
不过另一点挺有帮助的
But the-the other thing was helpful.
快看
Oh. Look at that.
杰出作家  代表作有漫画《睡魔》系列  小说《星辰》《美国众神》
-尼尔·盖曼发推特说了我的店  -他说什么了
- Neil Gaiman tweeted about my store! - What did he say?
"大家下次如果去帕萨迪那市
Uh, "Next time you're in Pasadena,
记得去这家店"漫画中心"看看
Check out The Comic Center.
店内气氛良好  传统漫画店风格
Great vibe, old school,
店主也十分懂行"
the owner really knows his stuff."
这是不是太赞了
Isn't that amazing?
比不上他的《睡魔》  但我们也不能期待
Well, uh, it's no Sandman, but I guess we can't expect
他写出来的任何文字都是大作啊
everything he writes to be a masterpiece.
他什么时候来的你店里
When was he in your store?
完全不知道  他来我应该能记得啊
I have no idea. I think I would remember that.
振金很明显是漫画里最强的金属了
Obviously, vibranium is the most powerful metal in comics.
两天前
有比艾德曼合金强吗
What, more powerful than adamantium?
拉杰说得对
He's right.
金刚狼的爪子  奥创的外壳
Wolverine's claws, Ultron's outer shell.
还需要我再举例吗
Need I go on?
不用  但你估计还是会说
You don't need to, but you probably will.
那神奇女侠的手镯呢
What about Wonder Woman's bracelets?
说得好
Good point.
金属里的一霸  时尚界的一姐
Strong as a metal and fierce as a fashion choice.
其实呢
You know,
雷神索尔的锤子也很强啊
Thor's hammer's pretty powerful,
在漫画里是被附魔的乌鲁金属做的
and in the comics, it's made out of enchanted uru.
我觉得是附魔的部分让它强大
Uh, yeah, I think it's the enchantment
不是乌鲁自己本身强大
that's powerful, not the uru,
不过还是感谢你参与讨论啊
but, uh, thanks for playing.
可恶  真不敢相信尼尔·盖曼来你店里
Oh, man, I can't believe Neil Gaiman came in,
而我们却没在场
and we weren't even there.
第十一季  第二十一集
你看到水星了吗  你能看到吗
Can you see Mercury? Can you see it?
等一下啦
One second.
也就是罗马神话中的墨丘利[水星]
希腊神话中赫耳墨斯
You know, the Greek version of Mercury, Hermes,
当年在雅典受祭拜时
was worshipped in Athens
人们是对着巨大的阴茎木雕来祭拜祂
by the carving of giant wooden phalluses.
求你了  艾米
Please, Amy,
能不能从古雅典人的污秽思想里出来
get your mind out of the ancient Athenian gutter.
又涨一个新粉丝  我要火啦
Got another follower. I'm blowing up.
厉害  现在有多少粉了
Great. How many does that make?
两位数高段班
High double digits.
-90多粉丝啦  -两位数中段班
- The nineties? ?- Mid double digits.
佩妮  你想来看看吗
Hey, uh, Penny, do you want to check this out?
好啊
Yeah, sure.
好的  从这里看
All right, just, uh, look through here,
如果你想拍照  就按这个按钮
and if you want to take a picture, just push that button.
行
Okay.
那是什么啊
Oh, what is that?
是水星吗  我特别萌水星
Is it Mercury? I'm really jonesing for Mercury.
现在要看到水星还太早了点吧
I think it's a little early for Mercury to be visible yet.
玩欲擒故纵
Playing hard to get.
我就喜欢这样的行星
I like that in a planet.
有个模糊的东西啊
No, there's something fuzzy.
是你的少女岁月吗
Is it your teen years?
才不是
No.
是啦  你闭嘴
Yes. Shut up.
看  看那个  我好像看到什么了
Look. Look at that. I think I see something.
很可能是你的眼睫毛而已
It could just be your eyelash.
才不是眼睫毛
It's not an eyelash!
好吧  那你拍张照  我来看看
Okay, well, uh, take a picture. Let's see.
好了  拍好了
Okay. Here.
还真有东西
Hmm. I do see something.
-我就跟你说吧  -那是什么
- Told you. ?- What is it?
不知道呢
I don't know.
很可能是个彗星
Maybe it's a comet.
那就太酷了吧
That would be so cool.
你们想看真正的星吗  巨星就在此
You guys want to see a real star, look over here.
怎么了
What?
单口相声演员帕顿·奥斯瓦尔特的弟弟转发我了
I just got retweeted... by Patton Oswalt's brother.
尼尔·盖曼真的都来这里买吗
So, this is really where Neil Gaiman shops?
尼尔·盖曼  尼克拉斯·凯奇  娜塔莉·波特曼
Neil Gaiman, Nicolas Cage, Natalie Portman.
名单可长了
The list goes on.
他们都来这里买吗
They all come here?
除非是我撒谎了
Unless I'm lying.
这些人都是谁啊
Who are all these people?
怎么  快闪族有活动吗
What? Is this a flash mob?
他们有在跳舞吗
Are they dancing?
我又不知道这年头大家都怎么跳舞
I don't know what today's dancing looks like.
两位  那条推特真的吸引了好多人来
Hey, guys. That tweet actually got people to come in.
是不是超棒
Isn't that great?
才没有  我就喜欢这店以前那样子
No. I liked the way the store was before.
门可罗雀  惨不忍睹的样子吗
You mean empty and sad?
对啊  那简直完美
Yes, it was perfect.
仿佛有在卖宝可梦卡片的殡仪馆
Like a funeral home that sells Pokemon cards.
我现在要是想要
What am I supposed to do now
留在店里看看漫画该怎么办
if I want to hang out and read a comic book?
去坐在沙发上看啊
Go sit on the couch.
坐在陌生人旁边吗
Next to a stranger?
我唯一愿意坐她旁边阅读并无视的女人
If I'm going to sit, read, and ignore a woman,
只能是我未婚妻
it's going to be my fiancee.
你干嘛有点人群就唧唧歪歪啊
Why are you being such a baby about the crowds?
你不是也去漫展的吗
You go to Comic-Con.
你...  抱歉
You-- I'm sorry.
你把这里跟漫展相提并论吗
You're comparing this place to Comic-Con?
在这里  我能在上厕所时
Well, can I go to the bathroom here next to a Wookiee
碰见拉链卡到毛发的《星战》伍基人吗
who got his zipper stuck in his fur?
我们俩去漫展的理由还真是大不同啊
Wow. We go to Comic-Con for different reasons.
这样吧
You know what?
给我一份《动作漫画》第1000期
Just give me a copy of Action Comics 1000,
我买了就走
and I'll be on my way.
抱歉  卖完了
Sorry. All out.
你现在就随便放人进店里买吗
Now you just let people come in and buy them?
我没意识到你连自己灵魂都卖啊
I didn't realize your soul was also for sale.
本来没卖  但你出个价就能谈
Well, it wasn't, but, uh, make me an offer.
谁啊
Who is that?
-谢尔顿  -他又不爽谁了
- Sheldon. ?- Who is he mad at?
-尼尔·盖曼  -那是谁啊
- Neil Gaiman. ?- Who's that?
-反正不是我们  -太棒了
- Not us. ?- Great.
两位
?Guys.
你们猜怎么着
So, guess what.
昨晚那东西的确是个彗星
That indeed was a comet last night,
而且呢  是从未被人发现过的
and it turns out, no one's seen it before.
真的吗
Really?
快看  我发现了一个彗星呢
Look at that! I discovered a comet! Oh!
什么叫你发现的
What do you mean you discovered it?
是我看到它的啊
Well, I'm the one who saw it.
用我摆好位置的我的望远镜
In my telescope that I positioned.
你只是看了而已
All you did was look into it.
你们一起发现的
Well, you both discovered it.
可以在登记表上写上你们俩的名字啊
You can put both your names on the registration form.
-其实我们不能  -为什么
- Actually, we can't. - ?Why not?
因为当我填登记表时  上面问了发现者的名
Because when I filled it out, it asked for name of discoverer,
我写了"拉杰什·库萨帕里"  因为...
and I put "Rajesh Koothrappali" because...
那是我  是我发现的
because that's who I am, and that's what I did.
你不是吧
Are you kidding me?
的确  他才是知道那是彗星的人
Well, he is the one who knew it was a comet.
他知道个屁  他以为那是我的眼睫毛
No, he didn't. He thought it was an eyelash!
你还以为那是一条模糊的东西
And you thought it was a fuzzy streak.
你知道什么是彗星吗
I mean, do you even know what a comet is?
知道啊  就是我先看到的东西
Yeah, the thing I saw first.
我真心觉得你那样不能算是发现
I honestly don't think that that qualifies as a discovery.
但照片是我拍的
But I took the picture.
是因为我让你拍下来
Because I told you to!
如果照片是一只猴子拍的
Like, if a monkey took the picture,
难道彗星是它发现的吗
did it discover the comet?
你说啥
Excuse me?!
他不是想说猴子
Uh, he didn't mean monkey.
-滚出我家  -她不是这意思
- Get the hell out of my apartment! - ?And she didn't mean that.
好像真是这意思  你快走吧
Actually, I think she did. You should go.
你看起来好美
You look great.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
你能相信这是我
Would you believe this is actually a dress
怀孕前的裙子吗
from before I was pregnant?
不是要跟你比较啦
Well, it's not a competition,
但我举行成年礼时就是穿的这套西装
but I wore this suit to my Bar Mitzvah.
斯图尔特在哪
Where's Stuart?
我跟他说了我们订了六点半的餐厅
I told him we had a 6:30 reservation.
我打给他
Well, I'll call him.
漫画中心  这里的超级英雄就是你
Comic Center, where the real superhero is you.
斯图尔特  你不是要过来照看孩子吗
Stuart, you're supposed to be babysitting.
糟了  是今晚  我忘了
Oh! Shoot. That was tonight. I forgot.
店里忙翻了
The store's been really busy.
你几点能来
Well, when can you get here?
我应该来不了  听我说
Um, I don't think I can. Listen to this.
我刚才给一个客人收钱时  听到有人说
I-I was ringing up a customer, and I heard someone say,
"付款要排队啊"  我一看  真的有个队
"Hey, there's a line," and I looked, and there was.
不是吧  你怎么能这样对我们
Come on. You can't do this to us.
我真的很抱歉  我会补偿你们的
I am really sorry. I will make it up to you.
但补偿礼物不会是方·基默版的蝙蝠侠手办
But it won't be with a Val Kilmer Batman figurine
此版蝙蝠侠的观众口碑较差
因为有蠢蛋正要掏钱买这个
because some sucker's buying that right now.
不是说你  这手办超赞的
Not you. This is great.
他说他要工作
He says he has to work.
没关系
Oh, it's okay.
我们可以改天再过约会之夜
We can have date night another night.
但你都打扮好了
But you got all dressed up.
我们本来要享受晚餐和浪漫的
We were supposed to have dinner and romance.
我们分工合作就好了
We'll just have to divide and conquer.
我负责去吃晚餐
I'll go to dinner,
你可以跟网络在家享受"浪漫"
and you can stay home with the Internet and have romance.
我上网查过了
Okay, look, I Googled it.
我拍的照片  所以是我发现的
I took the picture, so it's my discovery.
他偷了我的彗星
He stole my comet.
我知道  但话说回来  你真的在乎吗
I know, but on the other hand, do you really care?
当然在乎  我总是遇到这种事
Yes, I care. This happens to me all the time.
大家看我一眼
People take one look at me
就认为我不知道自己在说什么
and assume I don't know what I'm talking about.
那一定不是真的
Oh, I'm sure that's not true.
不好意思  你是在说
I'm sorry. Are you saying
我不知道自己在说什么吗
I don't know what I'm talking about?
我什么都没说
No, I'm not saying anything...
再也不说了
ever again.
我是认真的  前几天在公司
Look, I'm serious. The other day at work,
我想出个好点子  但没人听我说话
I had this great idea, but no one was listening to me.
五分钟后  保罗说了同样的话
And then five minutes later, Paul said the same thing,
大家简直要抬起他欢呼了
and they practically carried him around the room.
什么点子
Oh, well, what was it?
去加州比萨厨房吃午餐
Well, CPK for lunch,
但这只是其中一个例子
but that's just one example.
我要打交道的医生也都这样
It also happens with all the doctors I have to deal with.
他们居高临下瞧不起我
You know, they're so condescending.
我受够了不计较这种事
I'm so sick of letting this stuff slide.
是我发现的彗星  凭什么让拉杰说是他发现的
I found that comet. Why should I let Raj say he found it?
我知道你说得对  但他是我们的朋友
I know you're right, but he is our friend,
而且这对他的前途也许有帮助
and this could be good for his career.
这么说你同意我  但他还是得逞
Okay, so you agree with me, but he still gets his way?
没错  大家都赢啦
Ah, there you go. Everybody wins.
天啊  你真是爱讨好人
My God, you're such a people-pleaser.
你无法忍受惹别人生气
You can't stand making anyone angry.
我为什么要想惹别人生气
Why would I want to make anyone angry?
因为那意味着你站在我这边
'Cause it would mean you were on my side.
我是站在你这边啊
Oh, I am on your side. Hey, hey.
我们别忘了你真正气的人是拉杰
Let's not forget who you're really mad at here-- Raj.
还有保罗  保罗最差劲了
Oh, and Paul. Paul sucks, right?
但别告诉他我这么说
But don't tell him I said that.
霍华德  你看到这个了吗
Hey, Howard, did you see that...?
我在这  谢尔顿
I'm over here, Sheldon.
刚才好险啊
That was a close one.
我差点就跟那哥们回家了
I almost went home with that guy.
你还好吗  我们要走吗
You doing okay? Do we need to go?
我没事
No, I'm fine.
我承认这些人一开始让我措手不及
I admit all these people did take me by surprise at first,
但我已经学会能接受改变了
but I've learned that I can accept change.
几时开始的
S-Since when?
艾米把她的普通洗发水
I managed it when Amy switched her shampoo
换成控油洗发水时  我就学会接受了
from Prell to Prell for oily hair. Hmm?
虽然我挺想念
Although I do miss the way
她头以前总滑下枕头的样子
her head used to slide off the pillow.
有什么能帮你的
May I help you?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是德妮丝  新来的助理经理
Oh, I'm Denise, the new assistant manager.
不要
Nope.
你能相信吗  在过去十年
Can you believe it? In the past decade,
我在那家店花了几千块
I have spent thousands of dollars in that store,
结果他就这样回报我
and this is the thanks I get.
你说得对  他至少该送你个杯子
You're right. I mean, he could at least get you a mug.
他有送我杯子
He gave me a mug.
不然我在用什么喝水
What do you think I'm drinking out of?
你都有在注意人家吗
Do you even pay attention?
老实说  越来越少了
Honestly, less and less.
艾米  漫画书店
Amy, the comic book store
对我来说就像《黑豹》里的那个国家
is like my version of the country in Black Panther.
我有预感接下来的话会
Okay, I'm afraid this is gonna get really offensive
冒犯到某些人种群体
to certain groups.
不过你说吧
But go on.
避世的瓦坎达仿佛一颗隐藏的宝石
The nation of Wakanda was a hidden gem,
他们也想保持现状
and they wanted to keep it that way,
因为他们知道一旦向世界开放
because they knew if they opened it up to the world,
那里所有特别之处都会被毁掉
everything that was special about it would get ruined.
-你说完了吗  -说完了
- Are you done? ?- Yes.
松了一口气
Oh, okay.
你说的既有道理又不冒犯人
That both made sense and wasn't offensive.
而雪上加霜的是  斯图尔特还请了个女员工
And to make things worse, Stuart hired some woman.
-冒犯要来啦  -不
- There we go. ?- No...
我不是烦她是女人
I'm not annoyed that she's a woman.
我是很烦  而她正好是女人
I'm annoyed, and she's a woman.
我懂
No, I get that.
我也烦  我也正好是女人
I'm annoyed and I'm a woman.
只是斯图尔特很了解我的喜好
It's just, Stuart knows my likes and dislikes.
而且如果我偶尔拿起了
And I can count on his discretion
超人好基友吉米·奥尔森的过期刊
if I pick up the occasional back issue
我可以信任他能保密
of Superman's Pal Jimmy Olsen.
我也绝对没看过那玩意
Which I don't.
别把她当作陌生人
Well, don't think of her as a stranger.
把她看成是
Just think of her as a...
你还没指责  说教或瞧不起过的朋友
a friend you haven't berated, lectured or condescended to yet.
我还没这么想过呢
I hadn't thought of it that way.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-不客气  -你机智
- You're welcome. ?- You're wise,
身上又有书的味道
and you smell like books.
你真是完美的天菜
You really are the whole package.
拉杰  帮帮我
Raj, just help me out.
佩妮真的很气彗星的事
Penny's pretty mad about this comet thing.
她不开心  我很抱歉
Well, I'm sorry she's upset.
-但彗星不是她发现的  -得了吧
- But she didn't discover it. - Oh, come on,
你知道她也有份
you know she was a part of it.
把她的名字加到登记表上吧
Just add her name to the registration.
但我已经告诉所有同事是我发现的
But I already told everyone at work that I did it.
我的上司超激动
My boss was so excited,
他都开始叫我彗星队长了
he started calling me Captain Comet.
这比他之前给我取的绰号"甜甜圈博士"强多了
Which is better than his last nickname for me: Dr. Doughnuts.
因为有一次我吃了两个甜甜圈
Because one time I had two doughnuts.
还有两次我吃了三个甜甜圈
And two times I had three doughnuts.
看来你得把自尊吞下去了
I guess you're just gonna have to swallow your pride.
我做不到
I, I, I can't do that.
当然可以  把它当成两三个甜甜圈就行了
Sure you can-- just pretend it's two or three doughnuts.
你不明白
You don't understand.
莱纳德  我需要这个
Leonard, I need this.
我上一个重大发现是
My last big discovery was
如果用力压住上唇
if you press your upper lip hard enough,
可以止住喷嚏
you can block a sneeze.
这是我告诉你的
I told you that.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
是我自找的
I brought this upon myself.
我是个差劲的科学家
I'm a bad scientist.
-我是个自私的人  -不  别难过
- I'm a selfish person. ?- No, no, don't get upset.
你不是坏人
You're not a bad person.
让我和...  佩妮谈谈吧
Just let me... talk to Penny.
我一定会让她理解的
I'm-I'm sure I can make her understand.
谢谢  你真是个好朋友  莱纳德
Thank you. You're a good friend, Leonard.
你知道就好  因为我说不定得搬来和你住了
I'm glad you think so, 'cause I may be living here soon.
看看她
Just look at her over there.
她刚上班
She just started,
就开始负责"员工推介"专栏了
and she gets to put up "Staff Picks."
我在这里晃荡10年了
I've been coming here for ten years--
连个"谢尔顿不喜欢"的专栏都没有
I still can't put up "Sheldon Dislikes."
我昨天和她聊了会
I talked to her yesterday.
她这人挺懂行的
She really seems to know her stuff.
我接受挑战
Challenge accepted.
我根本没这个意思
That is not what that was.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我希望
I was wondering
你能推荐点书给我
if you could recommend something.
好呀  能告诉我你喜欢的类型吗
Oh, sure. You want to tell me what you like?
我不
I would not.
你穿了绿灯侠的衣服
All right, well, you're wearing a Green Lantern shirt,
我猜你是DC家的粉丝
so I'm guessing you're a DC fan.
鉴于你这是第一代绿光侠艾伦?史考特
Although that's from the Alan Scott era,
所以你可能不太喜欢最近的剧情
so you're probably not super into the current run.
你喜欢设定在一战时期有龙和魔法的
How would you feel about an alternate history
架空历史剧情吗
where World War I was fought with dragons and magic?
那是我10岁时
That's what I wanted the theme
想要的生日派对主题
of my tenth birthday party to be!
到这儿来
Here.
看看这本书
Check this out.
这是科特·卜思科[漫威作家]的作品
It's by Kurt Busiek.
如果你喜欢架空历史
You know, if you're interested in alternate histories,
尼尔·盖曼写过一本书叫《1602》
Neil Gaiman wrote one called 1602.
抱歉  我们正在聊其他事呢
I'm sorry, we're in the middle of something here.
这书写得特别好  真的
It is pretty good, actually.
他把漫威的超级英雄
He takes the Marvel superheroes
放在了伊丽莎白时代的英格兰
and he puts them into Elizabethan England.
让我猜猜  大家都把X战警当成了巫师吧
Let me guess-- everyone thinks the X-Men are witches.
是的
Yeah.
你先买回家看看  如果不喜欢
Why don't you take this home, and if you don't like it,
我让你全额退款
return it and I'll give you your money back.
但你可别告诉斯图尔特
Just don't tell Stuart.
斯图尔特是谁呀
Stuart who?
-你去哪儿了  -我去骂拉杰了
- Where have you been? - I went to yell at Raj.
然后呢  他会把彗星还给我吗
And? Is he gonna give me back my comet?
说来有趣
Interesting thing.
你屈服了吧
Did you cave?
也许我屈服了  或...
Maybe I did, or...
也许我屈服了
maybe I did.
但我也意识到
But I did realize something.
我不需要为你出头
I-I don't need to fight your battles.
你...  你就是
You... you are
一个坚强又独立的女性
a strong and independent woman.
你有为自己发声的能力
You have your own voice.
引用另一位坚强女性水果姐的话
And, to quote another strong woman,
是时候发出你的怒吼[歌名]了
Katy Perry, it's time to hear you roar.
你是在回家路上想出来的吗
Did you just think of that on your way home?
你想要我怎么样  车上就放着这首歌
What do you want from me? The song was on in the car.
但这不代表
But it doesn't mean
这不是正确的
that it's not true.
你说的得确有道理
Well, you make a good point.
我要自己去找拉杰谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to Raj myself.
我知道这话我说得不够多
I know I don't say it enough,
加油哦  妹子
but you go, girl.
够了  别说了
That was enough.
这是怎么回事呀
What's all this?
我们错过了约会夜
Well, we missed our date night,
斯图尔特又要上班
and Stuart's working again,
所以我想我俩可以在家过约会夜
so I thought we could have a date night here at home.
你太贴心了
Aw, that's so sweet.
你在咱们的约会夜
Oh. So... is that really what you're wearing
就穿成这样吗
to our date night?
斯图尔特不在  孩子们又睡了
Well, Stuart's not here and the kids are sleeping.
我可以什么都不穿
I could wear nothing.
你还是先穿着吧
You might want to hold off on that--
第一道菜是汤呢
we're starting with soup.
你不是要加班吗
Wha...? I thought you were working late again.
本来是的  可德妮丝都搞定了
I was, but Denise has got it covered.
今天最好笑的是
the funniest thing happened today.
收银台的收据打印纸
You know the, uh, receipt tape in the cash register?
居然用完了
It ran out.
我都不知道它还能被用完
I didn't even know it could do that.
我们正要坐下来吃饭呢
You know, we were just sitting down to dinner.
来得早不如来得巧
Oh. Perfect timing.
我去洗手
I'll go wash up.
约会夜又泡汤了
There goes date night.
你开玩笑吧  斯图尔特来了  快去拿包包
Are you kidding? Stuart's here! Get your purse.
-我们出去吃  -那你做的晚餐怎么办
- We're going out. - What about the dinner you made?
对  斯图尔特
Right. Hey, Stuart!
炉子边的那听罐头汤归你了
That can of soup sitting by the stove, that's for you!
你用罐头汤来打发约会夜吗
You made canned soup for date night?
你还穿着睡裤呢  快走吧
And you wore sweatpants. Let's go.
然后原来德妮丝也非常喜欢
Oh, and it turns out Denise is also really excited
丹·索罗特版本的《钢铁侠》
for Dan Slott's run on Iron Man,
因为他也是她最喜欢的《蜘蛛侠》作者
because he was her favorite Spider-Man writer, too.
哎哟喂
How about that?
对了  猜猜谁正在帕萨迪纳读艺术学校呀
Oh! And guess who goes to art school right here in Pasadena.
我不知道
Hmm. I don't know.
德妮丝吗
Denise?
你可真会猜  艾米
You're a good guesser, Amy.
不过没有德妮丝猜得准
Not as good as Denise, though.
她猜我会喜欢《 阿罗史密斯》这本漫画
She thought I would like this comic,
结果她猜对了
Arrowsmith, and she was right.
店里是不是很多人呀
Well, was the store crowded?
肯定很多  你不喜欢拥挤吧
I bet it was. I know you hate that.
是很多  可是如果人不多
It was. But if it weren't for the crowds,
斯图尔特也不会雇用德妮丝了
Stuart never would have hired Denise,
她真的超棒
and she's the best.
你就是德妮丝吧
You must be Denise.
是的  有什么需要帮忙的吗
Oh, yeah. How can I help you?
我是艾米  谢尔顿的未婚妻
I'm Amy, Sheldon's fiancee.
哇  老实说
Oh. I got to be honest,
我还怀疑过你是不是真实存在的
I wasn't a hundred percent sure you were real.
我就是本尊  我听说你今天和谢尔顿聊漫画
Oh, I am. And I heard you and Sheldon had a great time today
聊得很开心
talking about comic books.
-没错  -那就好
- We did. ?- Great.
事情是这样的
Here's what's gonna happen.
你得教会我怎么做
You're gonna teach me how to do that.
做什么
Do what?
假装喜欢看漫画
Pretend to like comic books.
可我是真的喜欢看漫画
Oh, no, I actually like comic books.
我们就不要纠结于语义问题了
All right, let's not get hung up on semantics.
天色已晚  我们还有很多活儿要做
It's late, we got a lot of work to do.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我还什么都没说呢
I haven't even said anything yet.
我知道  可我听到你上楼梯的脚步声
I know, but I heard your footsteps coming up the stairs,
一听就怒气冲冲
and they sounded angry.
的确是火大的脚步声  我在生你气
They are angry. I'm mad at you.
你确实应该生气
And you have every right to be, okay?
我...  实在太不地道了
I was being... I was being a jerk.
我们一起发现的  而我把功劳都抢走了
We did this together, and I hogged all of the credit.
这些年你都一直对我很好
And after you've been such a good friend to me over the years.
如果不是你
Like, I wouldn't even be able
我都不能和女生说话
to talk to women if it wasn't for you, so...
所以我会确保彗星上也有你的名字
so I'm... I'm gonna make sure that your name is on the comet.
谢谢
Thank you.
就算这对我工作上来说很丢人
Even if it's professionally embarrassing.
也许会让我的职业生涯岌岌可危
You know, or maybe put me on thin ice at work.
也许会让我失去科研拨款
I may lose my funding.
我还是想做正确的事
I still, uh... still want to make this right.
很好  回见了
Good. Bye.
这招对莱纳德有用多了
That worked way better with Leonard.
-回来了  -你回来啦
- Hello. - Hi.
你怎么在看漫画呀
Why are you reading a comic book?
德妮丝推荐给我的
Denise recommended it to me.
《DC宇宙重生》合订本
It's the Rebirth omnibus.
她觉得这本可以成为
She thought it would be a good entry point for me
我进入DC宇宙的入门书  而我不得不说
into the DC Universe-- and I have to say,
-我真的喜欢  -你知道  艾米
- I really do like... - You know, Amy,
艾米  我今天聊了太多漫画了
Amy, I've talked a lot about comic books lately.
我们聊点其他的吧
Can we talk about something else?